tutorvista.co.in 2009-08-05

# Privacy Policy

## Privacy Statement Effective as of August, 2006

## TutorVista.com Privacy statement

#### Customer Care

Click to get customer service, technical support and subscription help.

TutorVista.com has created this privacy statement ("Statement") in order to demonstrate our commitment to customer privacy. Privacy on the TutorVista.com web site (the "Site") is of great importance to us. Because we gather important information from our visitors and customers, we have established this Statement as a means to communicate our information gathering and dissemination practices. We reserve the right to change this Statement at any time, so please visit TutorVista.com regularly to review our privacy statement. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should contact the Privacy Program Office of TutorVista.com by emailing [care@tutorvista.com](mailto:care@tutorvista.com)., or by 24X7 online chat. 

## Collected Information

We require customers who register to use the services offered on our Site (collectively, the "Service") to give us contact information, such as their name, address, phone number, and e-mail address, and billing information, such as billing name and address, credit card number, and the school grade and subjects to use the service. We also receive and may store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many Web sites, we use "cookies" and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses www.tutorvista.com. More information on our use of "cookies" can be found below. 

TutorVista.com uses the information that we collect to set up the Service for our customers. We may also use the information to contact customers to further discuss customer interest in our company, the Service that we provide, and to send information regarding our company or partners, such as promotions and events. Customer email addresses and any personal customer information will not be distributed or shared with third parties. Customers can opt out of being contacted by us, or receiving such information from us, at any time by sending an email to [care@tutorvista.com](mailto:care@tutorvista.com). Separately, customers are also asked to provide an email address when registering for the Service, in order to receive a username and password. We may also email information regarding updates to the Service or company, and will send a Customer Newsletter. 

In order to tailor our subsequent communications to you and continuously improve our products and services (including registration), we may also ask you to provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, experience with our products and services, and more detailed contact preferences. Customers and visitors always have the option of choosing not to provide us with this information. 

Except as we explicitly state at the time we request information, we do not disclose to third parties the information provided. All financial and billing information that we collect through the Site is used solely to check the qualifications of prospective customers and to bill for the Service. This billing information is not used by TutorVista.com for marketing or promotional purposes. TutorVista.com uses a third-party intermediary to manage the credit card processing. This intermediary uses the information for the sole purpose of credit card processing. 

TutorVista.com may also collect certain information from visitors to and customers of the Site, such as Internet addresses. This information is logged to help diagnose technical problems, and to administer our Site in order to constantly improve the quality of the Service. We may also track and analyze non-identifying and aggregate usage and volume statistical information from our visitors and customers and provide such information to third parties. 

## Special Relationships

TutorVista.com has a number of relationships with business partners with whom we may share your personal information for the purpose of providing a service, fulfilling an order or completing a transaction. For example, we use certain vendors for the purpose of providing credit card transaction and check processing services. These vendors verify your purchase information, such as credit card number or checking account number, and authorize your transaction. In doing so, they have access to data about users, but they are prohibited from using this information for any other purpose. We also strongly urge you to read the privacy policy of our business partner at the business partners site. 

## Cookies

TutorVista.com uses software tags called "cookies" to identify customers when they visit our site. Cookies are used to remember user preferences and maximize performance of our services. The information we collect with cookies is not sold, rented, or shared with any outside parties. Users who disable their Web browser's ability to accept cookies will be able to browse our Website but will not be able to successfully use our Service. 

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close you browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file. Persistent cookies enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. 

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by TutorVista.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 

**Third Party Cookies:** We may from time to time engage third parties to track and analyze non-personally identifiable usage and volume statistical information from visitors to our website to help us administer our website and improve its quality. Such third parties may use cookies to help track visitor behavior. Such cookies will not be used to associate individual website visitors to any personally identifiable information. All data collected by such third parties on behalf of [TutorVista.com](http://www.tutorvista.com/) is used only to provide us with information on site usage and is not shared with any other third parties. 

## Web Beacons

Web pages may contain an electronic file called a web beacon, that allows a web site to count users who have visited that page or to access certain cookies. TutorVista uses web beacons in the following ways: 

Within the TutorVista web sites

  * TutorVista uses web beacons within the TutorVista web sites in order to count users and to recognize users by accessing TutorVista cookies. 
  * Being able to access TutorVista cookies allows us to personalize your experience when you visit TutorVista web sites that are located both on and off of the tutorvista.com domain. 

## HTML eMail

TutorVista's practice is to include web beacons in HTML-formatted email messages (messages that include graphics) that TutorVista, or its agents, sends in order to determine which email messages were opened and to note whether a message was acted upon. 

In general, any file served as part of a web page, including an ad banner, can act as a web beacon. TutorVista may also include web beacons from other companies within pages served by TutorVista so that TutorVista's advertisers may receive auditing, and reporting. 

## Log Files

TutorVista.com maintains log files of the traffic that visits our site. We do not link any information gathered in these log files to personally identifying information. Log files are used to manage traffic loads and information technology requirements for providing reliable service. Information collected includes IP addresses and browser types. 

## Information Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

All information gathered on the site is stored and maintained in secure facilities that limit access to authorized personnel only. 

## Retention of Information

TutorVista.com will keep personal information of its users for as long as they are registered subscribers or users of our products and services, and for a reasonable time thereafter. 

## Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site. 

## Change in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. 

## Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us by emailing [care@tutorvista.com](mailto:care@tutorvista.com), or by 24X7 online chat.
